Finding Aid for George Cacioppo papers, 1939-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sound Recordings
  - Cacioppo recordings
    - Cassiopeia
      - Cassiopeia in New York, Takes 3-4, Take 3 (10:27) and 4 (12:10), 7 in. reel, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 8]
      - Cassiopeia in New York, Take 5, 7 in. reel, 10:38, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 9]
      - Concert I: Cassiopeia, 7 in. reel, 5:16, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 10]
      - Concert II: Cassiopeia, 7 in. reel, 5:12, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 11]
      - Cassiopeia #1, 5 in. reel (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 12]
      - Cassiopeia #3, 5 in. reel (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 13]
      - Tape Performance of Cassiopeia, 5 in. reel (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 14]
      - Concert: Cacioppo Cassiopeia; Cage Variation II; Kosugia? Organic; Wolff Edgar; Bekaert Thoreau, 7 in. reel (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 15]
      - Scavarda: Piano Pieces & Landscape; Cacioppo: Cassiopeia Time (Twice), 7 in. reel, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 16]
      - Cassiopeia, Richard Sheff, electric guitar, Robert Sheff, electric organ, with tape (realization and audio generator by Bob Sheff), performed at "Everybody Wins," January 17, 1968, Canterbury House, Ann Arbor, Mich., 7 in. reel, 7 1/2 ips, stereo copy from mono master (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 17]
      - Cassiopeia 1 & 2, 7 in. reel, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 18]
      - Cassiopeia (Sheff), 7 in. reel (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 19]
      - Cassiopeia in Grand Rapids May 16, 1969, 7 in. reel, 16:44, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
        [Tape no. 20]
    - Mod 3, 5 in. reel, 4:46 (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 22]
    - Mod 3, dub, 5 in. reel, 4:46, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 23, stored in Box 20]
    - Moves Upon Silence, Contemporary Directions Ensemble February 23, 1980, 7 in. reel, two track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 24]
    - The Advance of the Fungii, Master, 7 in. reel, 14:26, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 25]
    - The Advance of the Fungii, 7 in. reel, 10:54 (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 26]
    - The Advance of the Fungii, WKAR Listener's Choice Program presentation, 7 in. reel (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 28]
    - The Advance of the Fungii, 2nd Performance, WKAR Listener's Choice July 24, 1965, 7 in. reel (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 29]
    - Concert: Robert Ashley She Was a Visitor (5:46); Donald Scavarda Matrix (2:00); Gordon Muma Greys (3:10); George Cacioppo Time on Time in Miracles (9:43), 7 in. reel (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 30]
    - Time on Time in Miracles dub from tape no. 30, ONCE Chamber Ensemble, Peggy Ericson, soprano, Max Neuhaus, percussionist, 5 in. reel, 9:43, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 31, stored in Box 20]
    - Time on Time in Miracles dub from Nancy Gordon recital, NIU, 7 in. reel, two track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 32]
    - Time on Time in Miracles Penn Contemporary Players, 7 in. reel (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 33]
    - Holy Ghost Vacuum, or America Faints; Side 2 Cage Avia; Rodgers Processional; Leedy Quaderno Rossiniano, 7 in. reel, 1/4 track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 34]
    - Excerpt from Holy Ghost Vacuum, or America Faints, 5 in. reel, 9:14, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 35]
    - K, 7 in. reel, 21:40, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 37]
    - Piano Piece #11 (Informed Sources) 4 hands-William Albright and Kurt Carpenter, 5 in. reel, 14:43 (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 40]
    - Piano Piece #11 (Informed Sources) 4 hands-William Albright and Kurt Carpenter, 5 in. reel, mono recording, 14:42 (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 41]
    - Informed Sources (Pianopiece #11), Max Lifchitz pianist, 5 in. reel, 10:19, full track mono, 7 1/2 ips (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 42]
    - Informed Sources (Pianopiece #11) unknown pianist, 5 in. reel, 14:47 (Box 18)
      [Tape no. 43]
    - Dream Concert, 7 in. reel, 1/2 track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 95]
    - Pink Nightgown, 5 in. reel, 1:08, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 44]
    - Piano Pieces 4-10, 7 in. reel, 15 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 45]
    - Cacioppo concert, NIU April 8, 1976, Contents: Cassiopeia/Advance of the Fungii, 7 in. reel, 1/2 track, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 50]
    - Once Festival 1963 WUOM Program #4: The Music of George Cacioppo, broadcast June 8, 1963, Contents: Bestiary I: Eingang et alia, Piano Pieces, Trio maybe, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 51]
    - Cacioppo program/interview, WUOM Midweek Michigan Insert, Modern Music February 12, 1965, 5 in. reel, 8:15, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 52]
    - Cacioppo Commentary on North Campus 1963-1964, the building of the school of music, introduced and read by Fred Hindley announcer, quote of George, on science and art, 5 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 53]
  - Cacioppo recordings only partially identified
    - Tape Piece, unclear authorship, possibly done for space theatre electronic gating, full track monaural tape, 7 1/2 ips, less than 4:00, 5 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 54]
    - Source for Tape Piece #1. Vocal Sounds, 3 3/4 or 7 1/2 ips unsure, 5 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 55]
    - Tape Piece, stereo different piece than previous inside the piano sounds with overdubbing, early 1960s, 7 in. reel, 15:00 plus (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 56]
    - Tape Piece, vocal sounds, 7 in. reel, 10:00 plus, stereo maybe 1/4 track (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 57]
    - Six Piano Pieces October 18, 1968 7 bands of piano solos recorded in studio, edited with leader, possibly Mumma's studio., 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 58]
    - The Grate Society Birthday Concert October 23, 1965, contents Morris, Peck, Andrew, Albright music, edited tape, 7 in. reel, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 59]
    - WDTM Broadcast of ONCE Music, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 60]
    - (Garbled) piano/pitch wavers, 5 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 61]
    - Box marked: Is this Something of Cacioppo's?, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 62]
    - Cassiopeia master?, 10 in. reel (Box 22)
      [Tape no. 63]
    - Robert Ashley Interview November 1975, 10 in. reel (Box 22)
      [Tape no. 64]
    - Honors Dialog of January 26, 1972, Ident & Change, 10 in. reel, 41:30, 7 1/2 ips (Box 22)
      [Tape no. 65]
    - An Interview with George Cacioppo or "America Faints," September 23, 1974, 10 in. reel, 7 1/2 ips (Box 22)
      [Tape no. 66]
    - Program in Honor of George Cacioppo's birthday September 24, 1974, 10 in. reel, 7 1/2 ips (Box 22)
      [Tape no. 67]
    - Promo ONCE 1968 ONCE concerts announcements, 7 in. reel, 2:45, 15 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 73]
    - New Music program tape "acoustic properties" works by Cacioppo (Holy Ghost), Cage and Scavarda, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 74]
    - Hurrica C!! piano pieces, sounds like Cacioppo's improvisation, called-in suggestion by listener, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 78]
    - WKAR tape, interview of Cacioppo on WKAR November 1963 by phone on Advance of the Fungii, assumes there is a performance, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 79]
    - Edited tape of piano music unknown (?) works, high probability Cacioppo's work, 4 band tape 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 85]
    - Tape of an orchestral piece could be checked to see if it's Cacioppo's early piece, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 92]
    - A piano version of Cassiopeia possibly; Piano Piece, 5 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 93]
    - Cassiopeia 2 piano version, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 97]
    - Cassiopeia 3, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 100]
    - Cassiopeia 1, 7 in. reel (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 102]
    - Cacioppo cont. for NPR September 18, 1971 Milton Cohen background program narrated by him, sounds like an historical summary, 7 in. reel, 9:16, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 105]
    - Midweek Michigan, WKAR February 17, 1965 host Rob Doley, topic on modern art forms in which Cacioppo is interviewed, 7 in. reel, 33:00, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 108]
    - Campus News, WUOM, "ONCE is Too Much," February 3, 1965 Fred Hindley announcer, announcement for 1965 concert, Mumma is interviewed/included, 7 in. reel, 15 ips (Box 19)
      [Tape no. 116]
  - Cacioppo recordings unnumbered
    - K (short version), 5 in. reel, 5:05 (Box 19)
    - Moves Upon Silence, for two amplified cymbals and large percussion orchestra, 5 in. reel, 8:35, 2 track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
    - Overture 1952, Royal Oak Symphony Orchestra, William Boyer, conductor, 5 in. reel, 8:37, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
    - Overture 1952, Royal Oak Symphony Orchestra, William Boyer, conductor, recording with highs added, 5 in. reel, 8:37, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
    - Piano Sonata 1951, George Exon, pianist, 5 in. reel (Box 19)
    - Nest, by Neil Waltzer, for George Cacioppo, Roslyn February 1971, 5 in. reel, 2 track, 7 1/2 ips (Box 19)
  - Other recordings
    - #1 Piano music unlikely that it is Cacioppo's Bergian, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 69]
    - #2 Piano piece, later a piece for soprano and piano, excerpts Eugene Kurtz's Animations, tape of excerpts, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 70]
    - #2 Piano music not identical to tape 70 could be improvisations, excerpts, enclosed sheet of explanation, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 71]
    - #4 Tape of excerpts with enclosed explanation probably experimental, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 72]
    - Evans Mirages, news program only, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 75]
    - Program on plant music by Susan Stamberg of NPR, 15 ips, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 77]
    - Tape of Eugene Kurtz's a, Strasbourg Radio Symphony Orchestra, Roger Albin, conductor, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 80]
    - Jacque! Tape of the music of Bekaert (?), can vaguely hear Cacioppo's voice, (7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 81]
    - 201 short, Penderecki piece (note: tape broke during the piece), 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 82]
    - 292 another excerpt tape, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 83]
    - 4x Low #3, piano long sustained chords, 7 in. reel, could be 15 ips (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 84]
    - Sound for K, El pn + pn, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 86]
    - Not Lilacs, Continua, Dubs 206, Music by Robert Morris, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 87]
    - C. Dub, a Timpani piece, dub of someone's recital, unidentified, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 88]
    - Upper 1-5, Morris' version of Piano Piece 11 before they were mixed, 7 in. reel, 15 ips (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 89]
    - LP 1-5 Morris' version of Piano Piece 11 before they were mixed, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 90]
    - Corrente Melody in B piano piece, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 91]
    - Sounds from an ARP synthesizer, 5 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 94]
    - Electronic sounds, [could be "K" by Morris (?)], 15 ips edited, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 96]
    - Illegible inscription on reel, edited electronic sounds, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 98]
    - ? electronic?, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 99]
    - Edited electronic sounds possibly not Cacioppo's, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 101]
    - Composer Misery, Charles Christopher Mark, a radio program, John Ciardi speaking on the state of artists, 5 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 103]
    - Master 20/20, a collage piece at first could be destined to be mixed together, instrumental pieces, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 104]
    - #1 another excerpt tape, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 106]
    - WUOM Fred Hindley show, "A Journey Back in Time," September 20, 1971 apparently Cacioppo wasn't on it, several friends interviewed, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 107]
    - Organ piece 1966 not Holy Ghost Vacuum, unknown electronic organ sounds or piece, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 109]
    - Piano/waver, electronic sound experiments with piano sound, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 110]
    - #3 excerpt tape, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 111]
    - (Hamon) piano chords, possibly improvisation, only several minutes, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 112]
    - AM Negative, Anderson/Galante (?), 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 113]
    - Piano/waver, 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 114]
    - Piano pieces unidentified (could be George), 7 in. reel (Box 20)
      [Tape no. 115]
  - Other recordings unnumbered
    - Finnish music, 5 in. reel (Box 21)
    - Medium size mograph 1963 cybernomically modified piano, 7 in. reel (Box 21)
    - Piano/waver, 7 in. reel (Box 21)
    - Plant sounds, 2 reels; 5 in. reels (Box 21)
    - Anderson, D., "Aurora Borealis" for four marimbas, "Bazooka #5" for piano, 5 in. reel (Box 21)
    - Blake, Eubie, from NPR, and rags June 9, 1971, reels 5-inch (Box 21)
    - Boulez, Pierre, "Rpons,", 5 in. reel, 1/2 track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 21)
    - Cage, John
      - "Fontana Mix," Realization for tape alone (11:39) and Aria with Fontana Mix, 7 in. reel (Box 21)
      - Interview with Klaus George Roy, 5 in. reel, 14:09 (Box 21)
      - Unidentified, 5 in. reel (Box 21)
    - De Young, Lynden, "Texture: Organ, harp, Celesta,", 3 in. reel, stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 21)
    - Imamura, Rae, 1 audiocassettes (Box 21)
    - Lachenmann, Helmut, "Accanto,", 7 in. reel, 27:10, mono, 7 1/2 ips (Box 21)
    - Mayzumi, Toshiro, "Campanology for Multi Pianos," Yagi Masao, pianist, 7 in. reel (Box 21)
    - Messiaen, Olivier, "Quartet for the End of Time," movements 8 and 5, 5 in. reel, two track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 21)
    - Reynolds, Roger, "Fiery Wind (1976)," American Composers Orchestra, Alice Tully Hall, 7 in. reel, 2 track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 21)
    - Roblitz, David, "Levitation Boogie,", 5 in. reel (Box 21)
    - Salzman, Eric, reels 5-inch (Box 21)
    - Stockhausen, Karlheinz
      - "Inori," Sdwestfunk Symphony Orchestra, Karlheinz Stockhausen, conductor, 2 reels; 7 in. reels, mono, 7 1/2 ips (Box 21)
      - "Trans" for large orchestra, 7 in. reel, 26:05, 7 1/2 ips (Box 21)
    - Warde, Ann, "Moving Shapes," Ann Warde piano, Stan Nishimura and Jeffrey Tann Pressloff trombones, and "Computer Music 1B," realized on Apple microcomputer and Wesleyan Electronic Studio synthesizers (including ARP2600) 1983, 1 audiocassettes (Box 21)
  - Other recordings unnumbered 10 in. reels
    - Music of Jacques Bekaert (Belgian composer) August 12, 1970, 10 in. reel 7 1/2 ips (Box 22)
    - Recital of Joplin, Albright, Bolcom, Lamb, 10 in. reel (Box 22)
    - Stockhausen, Karlheinz, "Inori," Sdwestfunk Symphony Orchestra, Karlheinz Stockhausen, conductor, 10 in. reel; two track stereo, 7 1/2 ips (Box 22)
    - Transition, Bruxelles, Palais des beaux-arts September 30, 1972, 2 reels; 10 in. reel; 19 cm/sec. (Box 22)
    - WDET, 2 reels; 10 in. reel (Box 22)
  - Phonograph records
    - Cacioppo, George
      - "Festival Overture (1952)," first recording, 10 in. disc, 33 1/3 rpm (Box 22)
      - "Overture in F," premier performance, Royal Oak Symphony Orchestra, William Boyer conductor; b/w "Piano Sonata 1951,", 10 in. disc, 33 1/3 rpm (Box 22)
    - Lederman, Norman, "Stereofernic Orchestra,", 7 in. disc, 45 rpm stereo, 3:00 and 3:03